Sean Haines

971-404-4048 • seanhaines13@gmail.com • Portfolio • LinkedIn • Github

SUMMARY

I am a well-rounded and creative individual with a team and client first focus. My professional experience ranges from building nationally recognized and award winning healthcare programs and high volume account management to building beautiful, user-friendly websites and web applications.

TECHNICAL TOOLBOX

Web Languages/Frameworks: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular.js, PHP, Ruby on Rails,

Bootstrap, Node.js, SASS/SCSS, JADE

Databases: NoSQL (MongoDB), Mongoose.js, SQL (MySQL, SQLite)

Software: Excel, WORD, PowerPoint, Visio, Outlook, Adobe Suite, Sketchapp

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development - 2015

Coding Dojo, Bellevue, Washington

Bachelor of Arts in Community Health Education - 2008

Portland State University, Portland, Oregon

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer, Sept. 2015 – Present Mentor Ventures, Inc., Kirkland, Washington

r Ventures, Inc, Kirkland, Washington

- Converting static Sketchapp designs to animated, cross-browser & mobile friendly compliant websites.
- Content publishing editing, including proofreading, spell checking, and content voice guidance.
- Main Development tools: Sketchapp, HTML, CSS(SASS), JavaScript, jQuery, MailChimp.

UX/UI/Web Developer, May 2015 – Present

Freelance

- Working to with clients to clarify content requirements, edits and updates.
- Create Wireframes, Mockups and Coded designs.
- Main Development tools: Sketchapp, HTML, CSS(SASS), JavaScript, jQuery.

Sean Haines

971-404-4048 • seanhaines13@gmail.com • Portfolio • LinkedIn • Github

UI Developer, Aug. 2015 – Sept. 2015

Avanade, Seattle, Washington

- I was brought on a short-term contract to assist in the ExxonMobil Fuel & Lubes Division to implement and develop new front-end resources and components.
- Main Development tools: Visual Studio, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS(SCSS), Angular.js.

Team Lead, Mar. 2013 – Feb. 2015

Project Access Northwest, Seattle, Washington

- Assisted with database development through hands on user experience and research. Was
 part of the super user implementation group assisting with program rollout. Continuously
 monitored and communicated database user experiences and troubleshooting with IT
 support and database vendor.
- Met with case management teams to discuss daily tasks and monthly goals. Closely supported the Program Director by maintaining daily planning and operations to ensure high levels of efficiency and customer service within the organization.
- Assisted with the screening, hiring and training of new staff while managing the day-to-day operations of the case management team.
- Coordinated new strategies and strategic process improvements. Communicated and execute process changes to internal and external care teams.
- Compiled monthly, quarterly and annual analysis reports showing the success and growth of all programs.

Case Manager II, May 2010 – Feb. 2013

Project Access Northwest, Seattle, Washington

- Restructured dental program's case management process to increase efficiency. Increased client referral numbers by 1,200% over 2 years.
- Managed high volumes of accounts that included: Scheduling appointments, data entry of incoming referrals, processing medical chart notes, enrollment applications, and clinical records requests.
- Handled the day-to-day communication and connections between clients, vendors, clinical staff, and program partners through email, phones, written mail, and in person.
 Developed numerous case management training materials. Conducted program evaluations. Experienced with Lean methodology.

Eligibility and Enrollment Specialist, Jun. 2008 – Apr. 2010

Coalition of Community Health Clinics, Portland, Oregon

Processed all client applications, enrollments and denials. I was responsible for the
coordination of patient to provider assignments, patient orientations, surveys,
appointments, and interpretive services. Assisted patients access health resources via
phone and email correspondence, while complying with HIPAA guidelines to ensure the
security of patient confidentiality. Supported programs through data management and
reporting, quality assurance, website editing and improvements.